LUCAS SEE, M.S.

CONTACT

509-637-6842 seelcs12@gmail.com

SKILLS

Programming:

- Python(Numpy, Pandas, SKlearn, Tensorflow)
- SQL
- R

Tools:

- GIT
- Docker
- Kubernetes
- Azure ML Studio
- Power Bl. Tableau
- Apache Pyspark
 Techniques:
- Machine Learning
- Statistical Analysis
- Time Series
 Forecasting

EDUCATION

University of Wisconsin, GB

2020-2023

Master's of Science (MS) in Data Science

University of Washington, Seattle

2013-2017

Bachelor's of Science(BS) in Industrial Engineering

PROFILE

Data Science professional with 4 years' experience applying statistical analysis and predictive analytics to drive business results. Broad experience in Python, R, and SQL with a proven track record of applying ML solutions to business problems. Interested in solving problems in the supply chain area.

EXPERIENCE

Functional Area Manufacturing Engineer, Intel

May 2022 - Present

- Developed analytic model for Test Wafer Forecasting using SQL and Power BI. Drove 5% reduction in Test Wafers and \$11M cost savings
- Developed Kmeans clustering approach to tool performance evaluation, deployed with Kubeflow, resulted in 4% accuracy increase over previous method
- Led team developing standardized tool performance reporting system resulting in \$200k annual savings
- Developed Supervised Machine Learning (Random Forest regressor) to allow inference on tool performance, driving \$4M savings
- Designed high dimension anomaly detection app for Factory Outlier Detection using Pandas, Sklearn, and Dash deployed on premise server

LTD Industrial Engineer, Intel

July 2019 - April 2022

- Developed capacity models to define tool performance and forecast capital requirements resulting in \$10M cost savings
- Produced Power BI-based capacity forecasting model combining multiple data sources and providing install priorities for \$50M construction program
- Developed CPLEX-based optimization model to identify optimal chamber configurations, saving \$4.5M

Manufacturing Engineer, Genie Corp.

June 2017 - June 2019

- Managed development and implementation of industrial control system, leading to reduction in core quality defect by 80%
- Developed Data Analysis tools to track production issues and drive resolutions, reducing reoccurrence by 15%

Projects

Master's Thesis: Machine Learning for Airline Delay Prediction; Investigated causes of commercial airline delays and used deep learning via Tensorflow to develop model capable of predicting future delays with 91% accuracy